The
hey guys Welcome to modern javascript from the beginning this is not a course on frameworks or libraries
or how to use a query.
This is a course on learning and building things with pure modern Javascript.
So who is this course for.
For absolutely everyone.
We're starting from absolute scratch the first section is all about fundamentals like data types arrays
loops functions all the basics that you need to know and explained in a way that doesn't suggest that
you know anything about programming.
Now just because the first section is geared towards beginners doesn't mean that this is a beginner's
course.
From there we're going to learn all about the DOM how to manipulate interfaces events Asynchronous JavaScript
with Ajax and fetch promises and other new features.
We're going to learn about object oriented programming both E.S. five prototypes and as 2015 classes
we'll also learn about things like regular expressions javascript patterns and much more.
Now I carefully formatted this course in a way that is modular it has modular learning sections where
we really dig into the code and use the console for output to learn specific aspects of the language.
But I also included about 10 different projects that range in size that allow you to build stuff based
on what you've learned.
So some are very small many projects others take up to 12 lectures.
The last project will actually be an entire front end to arrest API using no framework whatsoever.
In fact we'll even build a custom HGP library that will build using the fecche API along with a sink
in a way.
So why take this course well first of all you're going to learn modern javascript from scratch.
And I didn't format this like many other courses out there where it's all older yes 5 code and then
a little sprinkle of iOS 6 at the end you're going to learn the core fundamentals that have been around
forever along with the new features.
All modern browsers now support 95 percent of as 2015 are also called iOS 6.
So things like leten Konst aero functions template literals we're going to utilize these features throughout
the course and then when we do get to something that the browser doesn't support such as EIAS 20:15
modules I'm going to show you how to compile your code with web pack and babbel down to something that
all browsers can run.
OK another reason is because frameworks have basically taken over.
People are learning frameworks before the actual language.
This course will teach you how to build things without reactor angular and at the same time give you
more skills to be able to understand how those frameworks operate.
OK.
You're also going to learn your way around the DOM without having to use a query.
There's almost no need for a query any more vanilla javascript is more than capable of manipulating
the DOM.
You'll also learn about structuring and design patterns.
So here's a list of some of the major topics that will cover in this course for absolute beginners.
We have language fundamentals that will move to Dom and Appalachian events with no query S-5 and ESX
object oriented programming Asynchronous JavaScript with Ajax and callbacks as well as newer standards
like fecche promises and sync away things like Error handling regular expressions local in-session storage
aero functions maps insets popular javascript patterns and a bunch of projects to go with all of it.
So some of the included projects will include a task list with DOM manipulation as well as local storage
to persist the data alone calculator a number guessing game in object oriented application on creating
book lists even build a custom HTP library first with Ajax and callbacks and then we'll move on to fetch
promises in a sink away and then we'll move on to building API projects like the get hub finder using
the Get hub API.
A weather app using the Weather Underground API will build a pretty large project using the module pattern
which will track calories and then we'll build a complete front end to arrest API with ESX modules using
web pack and babbel And then along the way we'll have some many projects like a Chuck Norris job generator
to look at Ajax and how that works and externally pie's a profile scroller to give you an example of
how to use E-6 iterators and then we'll build a little state pattern interface where we can switch from.
Will create a bootstrap theme and we can switch pages based on the state.
All right so these are some of the things that we'll learn throughout the course and these other things
that listed here are things that we're not going to completely focus on and I'm going to fully explain
but these are skills you may pick up some more each time balance.
SS We're going to use frameworks like bootstrap for materialized CSSA skeleton CSSA you're going to
learn more about each requests get requests post put delete rest AAPI eyes we're going to be using something
called Jason's server on the last project where we can create a fake rest API for our front end and
we'll build the front end using E-S 20:15 modules.
So we'll be using web pack and babbel to compile newer features of javascript down to S-5.
All right.
So hopefully you guys enjoy this course whether you're brand new to javascript and programming in general
or whether you're already in the field and you're looking to sharpen your skills.
Let's go ahead and get started.